<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</title>
        <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/</link>
        <description>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@reachsumit.com (Sumit Kumar)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@reachsumit.com (Sumit Kumar)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Tuning Large Language Models for Recommendation Tasks</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Instruction-tuning methods enable open-source Large Language Models (LLMs) usage for building highly effective recommender systems on private data. This article highlights the latest research work on this paradigm of using LLMs for recommendation tasks.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ChatGPT-based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>With its outstanding performance, ChatGPT has become a hot topic of discussion in the NLP community and beyond. This article delves into recent efforts to harness the power of ChatGPT for recommendation tasks.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Shallow Embedding Models for Homogeneous Graphs</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The previous article &ldquo;A Guide to Graph Representation Learning&rdquo; provided a comprehensive introduction to the state of graph representation learning, along with a review of the basic terminologies, techniques, and applications. If you are new to the graph learning domain, I&rsquo;d highly recommend you read the previous article first. This article takes a closer look at different types of shallow graph embedding models of homogeneous graphs. It also highlights a few real-world applications that build upon some of these ideas.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Guide to Graph Representation Learning</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In recent years, there has been a significant amount of research activity in the graph representation learning domain. These learning methods help in analyzing abstract graph structures in information networks and improve the performances of state-of-the-art machine learning solutions for real-world applications, such as social recommendations, targeted advertising, user search, etc. This article provides a comprehensive introduction to the graph representation learning domain, including common terminologies, deterministic and stochastic modeling techniques, taxonomy, evaluation methods, and applications.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Mixture-of-Experts based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) is a classical ensemble learning technique originally proposed by Jacobs et. al1 in 1991. MoEs have the capability to substantially scale up the model capacity and only introduce small computation overhead. This ability combined with recent innovations in the deep learning domain has led to the wide-scale adoption of MoEs in healthcare, finance, pattern recognition, etc. They have been successfully utilized in large-scale applications such as Large Language Modeling (LLM), Machine Translation, and Recommendations.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Diffusion Modeling based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Diffusion Models have exhibited state-of-the-art results in image and audio synthesis domains. A recent line of research has started to adopt Diffusion for recommender systems. This article introduces Diffusion and its relevance to the recommendations domain and also highlights some of the most recent proposals on this novel theme.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Zero and Few Shot Recommender Systems based on Large Language Models</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/llm-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/llm-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/llm-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Recent developments in Large Language Models (LLMs) have brought a significant paradigm shift in Natural Language Processing (NLP) domain. These pretrained language models encode an extensive amount of world knowledge, and they can be applied to a multitude of downstream NLP applications with zero or just a handful of demonstrations.</p>
<p>While existing recommender systems mainly focus on behavior data, large language models encode extensive world knowledge mined from large-scale web corpora. Hence these LLMs store knowledge that can complement the behavior data. For example, an LLM-based system, like ChatGPT, can easily recommend buying turkey on Thanksgiving day, in a zero-shot manner, even without having click behavior data related to turkeys or Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>Many researchers have recently proposed different approaches to building recommender systems using LLMs. These methods convert different recommendation tasks into either language understanding or language generation templates. This article highlights the prominent work done on this theme.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Twitter&#39;s For You Recommendation Algorithm</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/the-twitter-ml-algo/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/the-twitter-ml-algo/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/the-twitter-ml-algo/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Twitter has open-sourced a majority of its recommendation algorithm. It offers an exciting opportunity for researchers, industry practitioners, and RecSys enthusiasts to take a close look at how Twitter computes the recommended feed for the For You page. This article described Twitter&rsquo;s end-to-end recommender system along with relevant literature and code references.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Self-Supervised Contrastive Approaches for Video Representation Learning</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/03/contrastive-video-representations/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/03/contrastive-video-representations/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/03/contrastive-video-representations/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Advances in the contrastive learning domain have made it possible to reduce the performance gap between self-supervised and supervised learning methods. Consequently, it has enabled the potential of utilizing the vast amount of unlabeled big data. This article goes over state-of-the-art contrastive learning methods for effective video representation learning.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Positive and Negative Sampling Strategies for Representation Learning in Semantic Search</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/03/pairing-for-representation/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/03/pairing-for-representation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/03/pairing-for-representation/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Defining positive and negative labels for a retrieval task in a search ranking system is a non-trivial problem. This article goes over various sampling strategies for creating negative and positive pairs for effective representation learning. It introduces the concept of mining hard examples, followed by various strategies to sample hard positive and hard negative pairs. The article includes a lot of tips and learnings based on heuristics and empirical results from a comprehensive set of research papers published across the industry and academia.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
