<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</title>
        <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/</link>
        <description>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@reachsumit.com (Sumit Kumar)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@reachsumit.com (Sumit Kumar)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Prompting-based Methods for Text Ranking Using Large Language Models</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/12/prompting-llm-for-ranking/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/12/prompting-llm-for-ranking/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/12/prompting-llm-for-ranking/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive zero-shot performance on a wide variety of NLP tasks. Recently, there has been a growing interest in applying LLMs to zero-shot text ranking. This article describes a recent paradigm that uses prompting-based approaches to directly utilize LLMs as rerankers in a multi-stage ranking pipeline.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Generative Retrieval for End-to-End Search Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/09/generative-retrieval/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/09/generative-retrieval/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/09/generative-retrieval/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Auto-regressive search engines emerge as a promising paradigm for next-gen information retrieval systems. This article introduces this generative retrieval and the various latest techniques that have been proposed to improve its effectiveness.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Representing Users and Items in Large Language Models based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/06/llms-for-recsys-entity-representation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/06/llms-for-recsys-entity-representation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/06/llms-for-recsys-entity-representation/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Large Language Models (LLMs) have emerged as viable tools for various recommendation tasks. This article highlights various methods for incorporating users, items, and behavior data into the instructions for LLMs.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Shallow Embedding Models for Heterogeneous Graphs</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-heterogeneous-graphs-rep/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-heterogeneous-graphs-rep/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/shallow-heterogeneous-graphs-rep/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In previous articles, I gave an introduction to graph representation learning and highlighted several shallow methods for learning homogeneous graph embeddings. This article focuses on shallow representation learning methods for heterogeneous graphs.
While homogeneous networks have only one type of nodes and edges, heterogeneous networks contain different types of nodes or edges. So, a homogeneous network can also be considered as a special case of a heterogeneous network. Heterogeneous networks, also called heterogeneous information networks (HIN), are ubiquitous in real-world scenarios.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tuning Large Language Models for Recommendation Tasks</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/tuning-llm-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Instruction-tuning methods enable open-source Large Language Models (LLMs) usage for building highly effective recommender systems on private data. This article highlights the latest research work on this paradigm of using LLMs for recommendation tasks.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ChatGPT-based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/chatgpt-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>With its outstanding performance, ChatGPT has become a hot topic of discussion in the NLP community and beyond. This article delves into recent efforts to harness the power of ChatGPT for recommendation tasks.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Shallow Embedding Models for Homogeneous Graphs</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/05/shallow-homogeneous-graphs-rep/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The previous article &ldquo;A Guide to Graph Representation Learning&rdquo; provided a comprehensive introduction to the state of graph representation learning, along with a review of the basic terminologies, techniques, and applications. If you are new to the graph learning domain, I&rsquo;d highly recommend you read the previous article first. This article takes a closer look at different types of shallow graph embedding models of homogeneous graphs. It also highlights a few real-world applications that build upon some of these ideas.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Guide to Graph Representation Learning</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/intro-to-graph-representation-learning/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In recent years, there has been a significant amount of research activity in the graph representation learning domain. These learning methods help in analyzing abstract graph structures in information networks and improve the performances of state-of-the-art machine learning solutions for real-world applications, such as social recommendations, targeted advertising, user search, etc. This article provides a comprehensive introduction to the graph representation learning domain, including common terminologies, deterministic and stochastic modeling techniques, taxonomy, evaluation methods, and applications.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Mixture-of-Experts based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/moe-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) is a classical ensemble learning technique originally proposed by Jacobs et. al1 in 1991. MoEs have the capability to substantially scale up the model capacity and only introduce small computation overhead. This ability combined with recent innovations in the deep learning domain has led to the wide-scale adoption of MoEs in healthcare, finance, pattern recognition, etc. They have been successfully utilized in large-scale applications such as Large Language Modeling (LLM), Machine Translation, and Recommendations.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Diffusion Modeling based Recommender Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
        <name>Sumit Kumar</name>
    </author><guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023/04/diffusion-for-recsys/featured-image-preview.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Diffusion Models have exhibited state-of-the-art results in image and audio synthesis domains. A recent line of research has started to adopt Diffusion for recommender systems. This article introduces Diffusion and its relevance to the recommendations domain and also highlights some of the most recent proposals on this novel theme.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
