<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</title>
        <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/</link>
        <description>literature review - Tag - Sumit&#39;s Diary</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>sam.sumitkumar@gmail.com (Sumit Kumar)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>sam.sumitkumar@gmail.com (Sumit Kumar)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.reachsumit.com/tags/literature-review/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Collaborative Filtering based Recommender Systems for Implicit Feedback Data</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2022/09/explicit-implicit-cf/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Sumit Kumar</author>
    <guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2022/09/explicit-implicit-cf/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Different Flavors of Recommenders At a high-level, Recommender systems work based on two different strategies (or a hybrid of the two) for recommending content.
Collaborative Filtering: Algorithms that use usage data, such as explicit or implicit feedback from the user. Content-based Filtering: Algorithms that use content metadata and user profile. For example, a movie can be profiled based on its genre, IMDb ratings, box-office sales, etc., and a user can be profile based on their demographic information or their answers to an onboarding survey.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Towards Empathetic Dialogue Systems</title>
    <link>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2020/12/generating-empathetic-responses/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Sumit Kumar</author>
    <guid>https://blog.reachsumit.com/posts/2020/12/generating-empathetic-responses/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Recognizing feelings in the conversation partner and replying empathetically is a trivial skill for humans. But how can we infuse empathy into responses generated by a conversational dialogue agent or any of the text generation algorithm in Natural Language Processing? In this article, I will describe what empathy means through the lens of various academic disciplines and then do an in-depth review of the prior and current state-of-the-art NLU systems that can simulate empathy.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
